Mobile: +44 (0) 7552 167441 Email: erikjclark@icloud.com

Erik John Clark

Having been a pilot and commissioned officer in the Royal Air Force (RAF), Erik left to study Avionic Systems Engineering at university and lead all group projects tasked of him. Erik has a keen interest in the future of technology, demonstrated with his commended experimental work at university, a MSc project in place of his BEng project and has been undertaking a PhD in advanced target tracking techniques since. Erik is determined to achieve as much as he can in his lifetime.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Product Support Engineer

CMR Surgical: Apr 2021 - Apr 2022

- Network troubleshooting across multiple global sites and robot interfaces.
- Downloading and uploading data to AWS cloud.
- Redesigned the work process for the team's primary role, company-wide.
- Triage, escalation and investigation.
- Rewrote service level agreement with internal customers.
- CAPA investigation.
- Designed team training plan.
- Working within an Agile framework.

COVID Compliance Officer

Bernard Matthews: Oct 2020 - Feb 2021

- Generated presentations and weekly reports for executives.
- Chairperson for executive meetings.
- Research, propose and enforce COVID policy across multiple sites.

Tutor

Brilliant Club: Mar 2019 – July 2019

- Taught an extracurricular physics course about infrared light.
- Students of ages 13-15 year old.

Summer Internship (Systems)

GE Aviation: 2013 & 2014

 Above and Beyond Silver Global Award for distinguished contribution to customer critical project.

- Allocated to a 'tiger team' on a high profile project where customer relations were at risk.
- Authored numerous legal compliance documents.
- Authored and reviewed documentation to ARP 4754A DAL A standard.
- Wrote, and tested software to DO-178C DAL A standard.
- Led validation team for Remote Interface Unit.
- Started unique complex inter-unit communication analysis project.
- Created, configured, tested and integrated RIU internal test procedure in C programming language.
- Experience on R&D project.

Student

University of Liverpool: Sep 2012 – Mar 2022

- Student representative
- Studied towards PhD in Advanced Object Tracking Techniques.
- Farnell Electronic Component Company Prize 2013/2014.
- 2nd place in local IET Present Around the World Competition.
- 2nd place in Year 2 Project Video surveillance from a UAV.
- Presented student project to DSTL.

Pilot

Royal Air Force: Jun 2007 - Aug 2012

- Awarded Permanent Commission.
- Formal speeches.
- Completed rotary flying training mental agility, personal organisation, stress handling for prolonged periods.

Email: erikjclark@icloud.com

- Reviewed Major Accident Control Regulations document for highly strategic military base.
- Revised Nuclear Incident Plan for UK military base.
- Military Skills Course high stress situations.
- Completed Platoon Commanders Battle Course high stress situations.

SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

- C, Python, HTML5, CSS3, MATLAB, PowerShell.
- Secure Linux server setup.

Mobile: +44 (0) 7552 167441

- Website development.
- DOORS: Requirements management software.
- Presented conference paper at Fusion 2017.
- Various leadership roles: IET (All committee roles), Athena Swan outreach ambassador, university senate council, charity committee.
- Customer communications.

TRAINING AND CERTIFICATIONS

- 2005: Gold CREST Award from British Association of the Engineering Education Scheme in England.
- 2008: RAF Officer Training Completed Level 5 Diploma: Leadership and Management.
- 2010: RAF: Completed Military Helicopter Flying Training.
- 2011: British Army: Officer Training Course.
- 2014: GE Aviation: Skilled Level Architecture course.
- 2014: GE Aviation: Requirements Capture Course.
- 2015: University of Liverpool: Avionic Systems Engineering 1st Class BEng (Hons).
- 2021: British Army: Defence phase 3 trainer.
- 2022: AiCore: Machine Learning and MLOps.
- 2022: Microsoft: Building MS Teams Integrations and Workflows.
- 2022: Microsoft: Manging Windows and Surface devices.
- 2022: Microsoft: DevOps with GitHub.
- 2022: Microsoft: Protect Data and Manage Risk.

- 2022: Microsoft: AI Fundamentals.
- 2022: Microsoft: Enable Hybrid Work with MS Teams.
- 2022: Microsoft: Modernise Security and analyse threats.
- 2022: Microsoft: Manage your Frontline Workforce.
- 2022: Microsoft: Fundamentals of security, compliance and identity.
- 2022: Microsoft: Zero Trust.
- 2022: SANS: Fundamentals of Culture and Organisational Change.
- 2022: SANS: Motivating Change.
- 2022: SANS: Enabling and Measuring Change.
- 2022: SANS: Developing your Business Case.
- 2023: Agile Project Leadership.
- 2023: Project Management Foundations.
- 2023: Supporting workers with disabilities.
- 2023: ArcX Cyber Threat Intelligence 101.
- 2024: Udemy: Python: Zero to Hero (ude.my/UC-9f7b6846-28fe-4eeb-92a8-254b3f100377)

INTERESTS

- Fitness: running, gym.
- Charity.
- Researching technology: AI, quantum computing.
- Piano

CLEARANCES AND REFERENCES

Upon request.